<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Changes</title>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
    </properties>
    <body>

        <release version="0.2" date="unreleased">
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Enhancements to the POM editor:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The POM editor is now very lenient, and ignores
                        XML syntax errors, missing tags, missing closing tags,
                        and almost everything else you throw at it!<br/>
                        This allows the POM editor to be easier to work with,
                        and allows you to "write first, fix later", while
                        still leveraging the capabilities of a slick UI.
                        This was possible due to IntelliJ IDEA's excellent
                        PSI interface (kudos to JetBrains!).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        The POM introspection mechanism was refactored to be
                        exposed as normal Java beans, whose data is backed
                        by the underlying POM structure, thus exposing the
                        POM as a class. This not only simplified the code
                        in the POM editor and the plugin itself, but will
                        enable us to expose the POM structure to other
                        co-operating IDEA plugins that wish to interact with
                        the Maven POM files.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Added much needed support for editing dependency
                        properties. See the POM editor's "Dependencies" tab
                        for details.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        The POM Dependencies editor now allows you to browse
                        for a dependency via a Repository Browser, rather than
                        having to type in the dependency details!
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Added POM&lt;-&gt;IDEA synchronization inspections. These
                inspections let you know (on demand) if there are any
                differences between your IDEA project and your POM file.
                Currently supported are:
                <ul>
                    <li>Dependencies defined in POM and missing from IDEA modules</li>
                    <li>Libraries defined in IDEA module and missing from POM.</li>
                    <li>Dependencies declared in POM and missing from local repository.</li>
                </ul>
                Problems discovered are displayed in the POM Sync tool window,
                where you can apply one of the multiple auto-fixes for each
                problem.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                The goals tool window now supports Scroll To Source. If enabled,
                clicking a goal will scroll to that goal's source code, whether
                it is in your <i>maven.xml</i> file, or the actual plugin source
                code file (<i>plugin.jelly</i>) located in the Maven cache
                directory.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                The new Repository Browser tool window can now be used to view
                remote or local repositories. The browser is integrated into the
                IDE in your right tool window bar (the default).

                <p>
                    The browser supports downloading items to your local
                    repository (downloading entire artifact types, entire groups
                    or even the entire repository is supported!), and even
                    adding selected artifact versions to your POM as dependencies.
                </p>
            </action>
        </release>

        <release version="0.1" date="2005-05-29" description="The initial version.">
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                A graphical Project Object Model (POM) editor. The editor includes a
                standard text editor, as well as an intuitive user interface for editing
                the various aspects of a project.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Full synchronization between the POM text editor and the graphical POM
                editor, as well as with POM modifications outside the IntelliJ IDE.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Automatic discovery of POM files (<i>project.xml</i> and <i>maven.xml</i>)
                for each IntelliJ module. The plugin will detect if you create one of
                these files either from inside the IDE or from outside, and will respond
                appropriately.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                A special Maven side pane (also called a Tool Window) displaying the
                available Maven goals for the project. The pane shows goals defined in the
                module's <i>maven.xml</i> file, and common goals, marked as "favorites" in
                the module settings dialog.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Execution of selected goal(s) in a dedicated execution console which
                supports stop, pause, and re-run. The console supports copying the Maven
                output into the clipboard or into a text file.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Compilation errors reported by Maven in the execution console are displayed
                as links, which open the appropriate source code file at the appropriate
                location.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Auto-detection of your Maven home (via the <i>MAVEN_HOME</i> environment
                variable), and support for specifying a different Maven home (does not
                modify the environment variable).
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Easy installation via the IntelliJ IDEA plugins manager.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Support for assigning shortcut keys (hot-keys) for specific goals for a
                specific module in the IDE (no need to find the goal in the Goals tool
                window).
            </action>
        </release>
    </body>
</document>
