<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
        <title>TODO tasks</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Table of Contents">
            <p>
                This page displays the current tasks and features that need to be done.
                Each task or features might be assigned to a specific future release.
            </p>
            <p>
                Note that bugs are not maintained here - if you want to file a bug,
                please use our
                <a href="issue-tracking.html">issue management</a>system,
                or post to one of our
                <a href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>.
            </p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <a href="#Most_wanted">Most wanted (milestone and important features)</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="#Enhancements">Enhancements (smaller features)</a>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <a href="#Documentation">Documentation enhancements</a>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section name="Most wanted">
            <p>
                Features we want to (eventually) support in the IDEA plugin (note: some
                of these features might not even make it to the 1.0 release):
            </p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Feature</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Planned version</th>
                    <th>Assigned to</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Bidirectional update between IDEA project and POM</td>
                    <td>
                        Transparent bi-directional synchronization between the POM file
                        and the IDEA project files including:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Libraries synchronization</li>
                            <li>Descriptive features synchronization</li>
                            <li>Conflict resolution</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                    <td>0.1</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>POM Graphical User Interface editor</td>
                    <td>
                        Editor should support editing POM descriptive features (such as
                        homepage, issue-tracking URL, etc) as well as dependencies, SCM
                        versions, and build settings.
                    </td>
                    <td>0.2</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Jelly Text editor</td>
                    <td>
                        Provide a POM text editor, for those who prefer to hand-code
                        the POM. It should be a simple text editor, with Jelly namespace
                        recognition as schemas, as well as smart goal autocomplete.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>New IDEA project from POM file</td>
                    <td>
                        Add "New project from POM" action (think about using the Maven
                        IDEA plugin to generate the IDEA files - if so, it needs improvements).
                    </td>
                    <td>0.2</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Autolaunch Maven goals on predefined IDEA events</td>
                    <td>
                        Allow user to attach Maven goal execution to IDEA events such as
                        compilation, save, run, debug, etc. Allow specifying the timing
                        of preferred execution (before, after or replace).
                        We should also provide sensible defaults for this (but only after
                        user saw them - as this can cause unwanted results if defaults are
                        wrong).
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Automatic artifact download on need</td>
                    <td>
                        Automatically download required artifacts and/or dependencies.
                        Assuming the dependencies and IDEA libraries are synchronized,
                        we should always initiate a dependency update on project open
                        or when initiated by the user, to make sure project compiles
                        in the IDE to the correct classpath.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Repository Browsing</td>
                    <td>
                        Allow local and remote repository browsing and search. We should
                        also support user-initiated artifact downloads from the browsed
                        repositories (if remote).
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Create POM file from project</td>
                    <td>
                        Add a "Create POM file from project" action, to create a POM file
                        from an existing IDEA project.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Show help for goal</td>
                    <td>
                        Add option for viewing the help for a specific goal. We should
                        display both a Javadoc-like tooltip window showing the help for
                        the goal from the plugin's site in the goals.html link, as well
                        as the standard goal description (just in case).
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Show project help</td>
                    <td>
                        Allow showing the project help screen (like "maven -u").
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Maven Plugin Project type</td>
                    <td>
                        Add a new IDEA project type - "Maven Plugin". This will make
                        creating Maven plugins a snap. Project type should automaticaly
                        create the appropriate project.xml, plugin.properties, project.properties,
                        resources, etc for the developer. Also automatically activate
                        "plugin:install" before, run or debug, and other thinkable gadgets.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>WYSIWYG XDoc editor</td>
                    <td>
                        A sophisticated WYSIWYG editor for Maven XDocs for easy documentation
                        writing. If too complex (this can be a very complex job!) we should
                        at least provide a nice user-friendly text editor, that has a panel
                        with appropriate text fields for author name(s), email, document
                        properties, document title, etc.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Provide integration with Continuum</td>
                    <td>
                        An integration and UI for the Continuum (Maven's
                        Continuos Integration tool). Possible features could be:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Deploy project to Continuum</li>
                            <li>Check project status</li>
                            <li>Trigger builds</li>
                            <li>Ideas are welcome ;-)</li>
                        </ul>
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>

        <section name="Enhancements">
            <p>
                These are smaller enhancements and minor new features we want to implement
                in the IDEA plugin:
            </p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Feature/Task</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Planned release</th>
                    <th>Assigned to</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Allow automatic execution console close if no errors occured</td>
                    <td>
                        Allow the user to specify that the execution console will be
                        automatically closed if no errors occur during the execution.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Placing goals on toolbar and menus</td>
                    <td>
                        Allow adding goals to the IDEA toolbar and menus.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Support goal searching in goals tool window</td>
                    <td>
                        Due to the vast amount of Maven plugins, it would be nice if the
                        user could search the goals list.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Show goal descriptions</td>
                    <td>
                        (Done) We should show goal descriptions in both the goals tool
                        window and the favorite goals selection settings dialog.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Ask user to attach a POM on project open, if no POM is attached</td>
                    <td>
                        A nice feature could be to check on project open if there are IDEA
                        modules that have no POM attached to them, and if so - display a
                        dialog to the user about it, and allow her/him to open the module
                        settings dialog for POM selection. We should add a
                        "Never ask me again" checkbox, if this gets annoying ;-)
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Show favorite goals on relevant context menus</td>
                    <td>
                        Show favorite goals in the context menus. The goals should be the
                        favorite goals of the module to which the file clicked belongs to.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Show maven.xml structure in structure pane</td>
                    <td>
                        When the selected file in the project pane/editor is maven.xml, show
                        its structure more visually - e.g. list of defined goals, list
                        of defined goal hooks (preGoal/postGoal), etc. Link to source
                        automatically when double clicked.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Automatic license download on project creation/open</td>
                    <td>
                        Check if project has a LICENSE.txt file, and if not, prompt the
                        user and allow him/her to download a license from a predefined
                        list of known license (allow adding more licenses in the future).
                        Also set the &lt;license&gt; tag in the POM. Display a
                        "Never ask me again" checkbox if this gets annoying ;-)
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Add Maven plugin tips to IDEA startup tips</td>
                    <td>
                        Integrate into IDEA's startup tips mechanism and displays
                        various Maven-plugin related feature tips.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unscheduled</td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>

        <section name="Documentation">
            <p>
                Tasks to be done in the project documentation:
            </p>
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Task</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Assigned to</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Add a JIRA report to the site</td>
                    <td>
                        Automatically generate a JIRA report for the site.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Allow downloading SNAPSHOTs.</td>
                    <td>
                        Since the Maven xdocs plugin's downloads report that not
                        generate links to the SNAPSHOTs releases, we should allow
                        users to download these as well (especially until we release
                        0.1). This can be done by adding a link to
                        <a href="http://dist.codehaus.org/mevenide/distributions">
                            http://dist.codehaus.org/mevenide/distributions</a>in the
                        index page.
                    </td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Add screenshots to site</td>
                    <td>
                        Create and add some screenshots of the plugin to the site (either
                        index page or a special "Screenshots" link).
                    </td>
                    <td>Unassigned</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>