<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>maven-jbuilder-opentool-plugin</title>
    <author>Serge Huber (shuber2@jahia.com)</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Overview">
      <p>
        This plugin generates packages for JBuilder OpenTool extensions. It offers three different packaging types : 
        <ul>
          <li>Standalone JAR : all OpenTool resources are packaged into a single JAR, including all dependencies, making the package self-sufficient but also potentially quite large.</li>
          <li>Maven repository configuration : all that needs to be installed in JBuilder is a configuration file, which contains the path to all the required JARs pointing to the local Maven repository. This is not very useful for real packaging, but quite practical during the development of the OpenTool</li>
          <li>Relative location configuration : the configuration file is similar to the Maven repository setup, but this time all the JARs for the OpenTool are placed in a directory location relative to JBUILDER_HOME/lib/ext. For example for an OpenTool called "myopentool", the whole set of JARs could be located in JBUILDER_HOME/lib/ext/myopentool. This makes it quite easy to then update dependencies and or uninstall the OpenTool if required.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Configuration">
      <p>When using this Maven plugin, you must add the following property to your build.properties file :
        <ul>
          <li>maven.opentool.jbuilder.home : points to your JBuilder installation. Usually something like C:\JBuilderX under Windows. Under Mac OS X this will probably be something like : /Developer/Applications/JBuilderX/JBuilder.framework</li>
        </ul>
        This property is used for the opentool:install and opentool:uninstall goals.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Dependencies">
      <p>In order to specify which dependencies must be packaged in the OpenTool, the following property must be specified :</p>
      <source><![CDATA[
        <properties>
          <jbuilder.opentool.bundle>true</jbuilder.opentool.bundle>
        </properties>
      ]]></source>
    </section>
    <section name="Installing">
      <div id="documentContent">
      <p>
		To install the plugin automatically, please add the <code>http://mevenide.codehaus.org/repository</code> to your <code>maven.repo.remote</code> parameter.
		And use the plugin:download maven goal to install the plugin.
		<source>
	maven -DartifactId=maven-jbuilder-opentool-plugin -DgroupId=mevenide -Dversion=0.1 plugin:download
		</source>
	  </p>
   	  </div>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
