<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Changes</title>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <release version="0.1" date="2005-05-29" description="The initial version.">
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                A graphical Project Object Model (POM) editor. The editor includes a
                standard text editor, as well as an intuitive user interface for editing
                the various aspects of a project.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Full synchronization between the POM text editor and the graphical POM
                editor, as well as with POM modifications outside the IntelliJ IDE.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Automatic discovery of POM files (<i>project.xml</i> and <i>maven.xml</i>)
                for each IntelliJ module. The plugin will detect if you create one of
                these files either from inside the IDE or from outside, and will respond
                appropriately.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                A special Maven side pane (also called a Tool Window) displaying the
                available Maven goals for the project. The pane shows goals defined in the
                module's <i>maven.xml</i> file, and common goals, marked as "favorites" in
                the module settings dialog.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Execution of selected goal(s) in a dedicated execution console which
                supports stop, pause, and re-run. The console supports copying the Maven
                output into the clipboard or into a text file.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Compilation errors reported by Maven in the execution console are displayed
                as links, which open the appropriate source code file at the appropriate
                location.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Auto-detection of your Maven home (via the <i>MAVEN_HOME</i> environment
                variable), and support for specifying a different Maven home (does not
                modify the environment variable).
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Easy installation via the IntelliJ IDEA plugins manager.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Support for assigning shortcut keys (hot-keys) for specific goals for a
                specific module in the IDE (no need to find the goal in the Goals tool
                window).
            </action>
        </release>
    </body>
</document>
