<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Changes</title>
    <author email="mkleint@codehaus.org">Milos Kleint</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <release version="0.4" date="25/11/2004" description="Release for 4.0 RC1">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-115 - improved support for webapps. (JSTL)
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-63 and MEVENIDE-14 - inherited properties files taken into account in the UI.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-128 - better handling when pom file unparsable.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      MEVENIDE-72 - when changing version/artifactId/groupId suggest to update projects that depend on it.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Link pmd and checkstyle report output with the IDE's editor. Annotate the rule violations in the editor.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
       Additional properties panels, updated some other panels.
      </action>
    </release>
  
    <release version="0.3" date="28/09/2004" description="">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      New Maven project templates for creation of Maven plugins and Netbeans modules.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Added definition of autoupdate server for mevenide.codehaus.org.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Improved dependencies display, adding generated sources to Project view and to the classpath/completion.
      Also adding ear sources to Project view.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Most POM properties are already editable in the Properties... dialog. It's also possible to move definitions between
       the project's POM file and the parent POM it's extending. 
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">    
        MEVENIDE-92 fix.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">    
        MEVENIDE-83 - fix classpath dependencies resolution.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="0.2.2" date="21/08/2004" description="fix release">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">    
      MEVENIDE-77 - before running any goal, save edited files.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">    
      MEVENIDE-76 - completed the fix, also debugging of artifact works now.
      </action>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="17/08/2004" description="hotfix release">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">    
      hotfix MEVENIDE-76 - run project fixed.
      </action>
    </release>
  
    <release version="0.2" date="14/08/2004">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
    MEVENIDE-48 Global setting of dependency download progress display. A reaonable default set to avoid too much output.
    </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-37 fixed. (Nervous classpath scanning - IDE too often regenerated classpath info)
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-65 fixed. (a maven.xml based goal doesn't require a ':' character anymore)
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="fix">
      MEVENIDE-49 fixed. (JUnit integration works now)
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Maven output error parsing. Linking failed tests and compilation errors.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Added basic support for testing the project, single class and test. (MEVENIDE-50)
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Added basic support for running the project and running single class.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
      Added project view support for web apps.
      </action>
    </release>  
    <release version="0.1" date="17/07/2004">
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
        Initial release, allows to open maven projects within Netbeans IDE 4.0.
        Sources, test sources and resources are displayed within the project tree.
        UI updates on chanches in POM and properties files.
        Code completion on dependencies.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
        When project declares maven.multiproject.includes, projects included get opened as well.
      </action>
      <action dev="mkleint" type="add">
        Possible to execute arbitrary maven goal or sequence of goals. IDE actions and shortcuts are matched
        to relevant maven goals. The goals are customizable per project or user.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>

