<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
    	<author email="rhill@wanadoo.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
        <title>Help Page</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
    	<section name="POM Synchronization">
         	<div id="documentContent">
			<p>
				POM Synchronization View is being rewritten because the previous wizard lacked of ergonomy and simplicity.
				The synchronization process now is handled through a view (Eclipse View) ala "Team Synchronization".
				In its current state, it is far from complete and misses some features of the previous UI. However 
				multiproject support is much better now since it has been handled in the early stage.  
			</p>
			</div>
			<subsection name="Synchronization Process">
				<div id="documentContent">
			<p>	
				The synchronization View can be populated either through the project or the pom (project.xml, or more generally xml files) 
				contextual menu (Screenshot 1, below). In the later case, only the selected file will be involved in the synchronization process. 
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/sync_pom.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> synchronization Contextual Menu</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
				When triggered from the Eclipse project contextual menu, if multiple project.xml files are found in the selected project
				user will be asked to choose which POMs are to be included in the synchronization process. Also if any project.xml 
				inherits from another POM, this POM can be synchronized as well (Screenshot 2).
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/pom_choice_dialog.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> Project synchronization Contextual Menu</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
			</p>
			</div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Synchronization View">
				<div id="documentContent">
			<p>
				The synchronization View provides two visualization modes : 
				<ul>
				  <li>incoming mode displays artefacts (dependencies or directories) present in pom but not in project .classpath.</li>
				  <li>outgoing mode displays artefacts present in .classpath but not found in pom.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				In the future another mode will be available to show conflicting artefacts. Conflicts are still to be defined more clearly :
				<ul>
					<li>inheritance conflicts (much like the Maven Dependency Convergence)</li>
					<li>.classpath / pom conflicts</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				Inherited artefacts are shown using a decorated icon. Decoration is not customizable yet and inheritance is represented 
				by a rose triangle.
			</p>
			<p>
				Any artefact can be added or removed to and from pom or .classpath. Availability of the various actions depends of the 
				current vizualisation mode.  
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/synch_view.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Synchronization View</font>
				</center>
				<br/><br/>
			</p>
			<p>
				Artefacts (both dependencies and folders) synchronization can be customized through the properties view (Screenshot 4, below).
				Mevenide will provide support for Dependency properties through that View as well.
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/synch_properties.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Properties View</font>	
				</center>
				<br/><br/>		
			</p>
			</div>
          </subsection>
        </section>  
    </body>
</document>