<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
    	<author email="rhill@wanadoo.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
        <title>Help Page</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
    	<section name="POM Synchronization">
         	<div id="documentContent">
			<p>
				POM Synchronization View has been entirely rewritten because the previous wizard lacked of ergonomy and simplicity.
				The synchronization process now is handled through a view (Eclipse View) ala "Team Synchronization".
				Multiproject support is also much better now since it has been handled in the early stage.  
			</p>
			</div>
			<subsection name="Synchronization Process">
				<div id="documentContent">
			<p>	
				The synchronization View can be populated either through a container (folders, projects, ..) or the pom (project.xml, or more generally xml files) 
				contextual menu (Screenshot 1, below). In the later case, only the selected file will be involved in the synchronization process. 
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/sync_pom.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> synchronization Contextual Menu</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
			</p>
			<p>
				Under each POM node, only the artifact declared in this POM are dispalyed, if you want to synchronize a multiproject, you have to select 
				all relevant POMs from the dialog. Any artifact can be added or removed to and from pom or .classpath. Availability of the various actions depends of the 
				current vizualisation mode.  
            </p>
			<p>
				When triggered from an Eclipse container contextual menu, if multiple project.xml files are found in the selected container,
				user will be asked to choose which POMs are to be included in the synchronization process. Also if any project.xml 
				inherits from another POM, this POM can be synchronized as well (Screenshot 2).
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/pom_choice_dialog.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> Project synchronization Contextual Menu</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
			</p>
			</div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Synchronization View">
				<div id="documentContent">
			<p>
				The synchronization View provides two visualization modes : 
				<ul>
				  <li>incoming mode displays artefacts (dependencies or directories) present in pom but not in project .classpath.</li>
				  <li>outgoing mode displays artefacts present in .classpath but not found in pom.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				In the future another mode will be available to show conflicting artefacts. Conflicts are still to be defined more clearly :
				<ul>
					<li>inheritance conflicts (much like the Maven Dependency Convergence)</li>
					<li>.classpath / pom conflicts</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/synch_view.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Synchronization View</font>
				</center>
				<br/><br/>
			</p>
			<p>
				In the Outgoing mode (IDE to POM) Properties can also be attached to dependencies.
			</p>
			<p>
				Every synchronization node is adaptable and can vizualized in the properties view (Screenshot 4, below). In Incoming Mode,
				properties sheets are read-only whereas they can are writable in Outgoing Mode (IDE to POM).
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/synch_properties.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Properties View</font>	
				</center>
				<br/><br/>		
			</p>
			<p>
				You can filter the view thanks the Menu Manager using either regular expressions or selecting which nodes are to be filtered.
				This is an alternative to the 'add to .mvnignore' action.
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/sync_filter.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 5</b> Artifact Synchronization Filtering</font>	
				</center>
				<br/><br/>	
			</p>
			<p>
				Last, in Incoming Mode, another action is present in ActionBar that allows you to specify wether project.properties file should be written or not 
				(useful while dealing with jar overriding).
				<br/><br/>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/toggle_overwrite.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 6</b> Toggle Overwrite (Outgoing Mode only)</font>	
				</center>
				<br/><br/>	
			</p>
			</div>
          </subsection>
        </section>  
        <section>
			<p>
				<navbar prev="run.html" toc="help.html" next="edit.html"/>
			</p>
		</section>
    </body>
</document>