<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
        <title>Mevenide IDEA integration</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
                Welcome to the MevenIDE IDEA Integration project! This project
                aims to integrate <a href="http://maven.apache.org">Maven</a> in every possible way
                into <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com">JetBrain</a>'s IntelliJ IDEA.
            </p>
            <p>
                Current integration features include:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        An intuitive POM editor featuring both a graphical user interface and
                        a text-based editor. Both editors are completely synchronized. Moreover,
                        typos and syntax errors in the POM xml are absurbed by the user
                        interface which allow you to "write now, fix later". All Maven 1.0.*
                        POM elements are supported, and Maven 1.1/2.0 support is in the works.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Your Maven home is automatically detected via the <i>MAVEN_HOME</i>
                        environment variable. Custom Maven homes are supported, however.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        POM files are managed in a custom tool window, much like the known
                        Ant tool window. You may define as many POM files as you wish. The
                        tool window will also list the available plugins and goals, detected
                        from your Maven home.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Due to the enormous amount of plugins in Maven, you may associate selected
                        goals or plugins with a specific POM file, for easy access.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Execution of selected goal(s) in a dedicated execution console which
                        supports stop, pause, and re-run. The console supports copying the Maven
                        output into the clipboard or into a text file.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Compilation errors reported by Maven in the execution console are displayed
                        as links, which open the appropriate source code file at the appropriate
                        location.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Easy installation via the IntelliJ IDEA plugins manager (snapshot releases
                        are available <a href="http://dist.codehaus.org/mevenide/distributions">here</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Support for assigning shortcut keys (hot-keys) for specific goals for a
                        specific module in the IDE (no need to find the goal in the Goals tool
                        window).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Synchronization between the POMs and IDEA modules. This helps to make
                        sure that projects that work in Maven will work in IntelliJ, and
                        vice-versa. For example, you may synchronize the dependencies in your
                        POM to be defined in your IntelliJ module(s), or the other way around!
                        Other checks such as source directories, test directories, etc, are
                        coming too.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <subsection name="News">
                <p style="font-size: larger; font-weight: bold">
                    30 May 2005 - MevenIDE for IDEA 0.1 has been released!
                </p>
                <p>
                    This is the first release of the Mevenide for IDEA - and
                    brings Maven support for the popular IntelliJ IDEA, including
                    the ability to execute goals, a graphical POM editor,
                    automatic jumping from Maven errors to source code, and much more.
                </p>
                <p>
                    See
                    <a href="installation.html">installation instructions</a>for
                    information on how to download and install.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Help Wanted!">
                <p>
                    The Mevenide IDEA integration project is quite new and we are looking for
                    volunteers - you can help! If you like the IntelliJ IDEA, and you like Maven -
                    come and help us write the best IDEA plugin yet!
                </p>
                <p>
                    To participate - please contact us via our
                    <a href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Downloading and Installing">
            <p>
                Mevenide for IDEA releases can be found <a href="downloads.html">here</a>. If,
                however, you wish to use the latest snapshot version, you may find it
                <a href="http://dist.codehaus.org/mevenide/distributions">here</a> - search
                for files named <i>mevenide-idea-X.Y-SNAPSHOT.zip</i> (or ".tar.gz").
                Snapshot versions must be installed manually - see the
                <a href="installation.html">installation manual</a>for details.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Compatibility">
                <p>
                    Currently the plugin is only supported on the IntelliJ IDEA Early Access Program
                    (EAP) dubbed "Irida". It cannot be run on the 4.5 version. Latest snapshots
                    were tested against build 3430 (RC4) on Windows XP and Linux (Fedora and Debian).
                </p>
                <p>
                    There is, however, a port of the plugin for the 4.5 version with provides the basic
                    features such as per-module POM attachment, favorite goals, running goals and
                    jumping to source code from Maven error messages. It is available
                    <a href="http://www.codehaus.org/~arik/dist/mevenide-idea-4.5.4.zip">here</a>.
                    <br/>
                    NOTE: This is a source code distribution, and you will have to build it from
                    source code. If you do, make sure you compile the classes using IDEA, since
                    the plugin utilizes the IDEA UI designer, which injects bytecode into the
                    classes. There is an Ant script inside, but it does not perform the code
                    injection, and you will get exceptions. The Ant script DOES, however, provide
                    an Ant task for it, but does not activate it.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>