<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="rhill2@free.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
		<title>Mevenide Nature</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="Nature and Builder">
		    <subsection name="Overview">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p>
						Since version 0.3.0 Mevenide provides its own nature and builder. Mevenide builder 
						allows to activate/disactivate goals depending on the files that have changed since 
						last Maven run. Mevenide supports also AutoBuild now through the same mechanism. 
						<br/>
						The Builder is associated with the Mevenide Nature and only the projects that have Mevenide 
						Nature can benefit from the features described here.
					</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Nature">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p>
						Mevenide Nature is merely a marker whose sole purpose is to activate Mevenide Builder for 
						specific projects. Mevenide nature is attached by default to New projects created through 
						the <a href="wizard.html#Maven Project Wizard">"New Maven Project" Wizard</a>. 
						<br/>
						It can added to or removed from a project through the project contextual menu (Screenshot 1).
						<br/>
						<center>
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/builder/nature_management.png"/>
							<br/>
								<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> Adding and removing Mevenide nature</font>
							<br/>
						</center>
					</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Builder">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p>
						Builder activation works in a similar way than regular Maven launch (describe process 
						arguments basedir through the same interface), but requires additional settings to
						specify which files modification will trigger the activation of a particular goal.
						<br/>
						The builder configuration dialog can be popped up through the 'Project' menu (Screenshot 2).
						<br/>
						<center>
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/builder/builder_configuration_menu.png"/>
							<br/>
								<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> Builder configuration menu</font>
							<br/>
						</center>
					</p>
					<p>
						This brings up a similar dialog than the Mevenide External Tools integration dialog (Figure 2).
						The big difference lies in the third tab : in the 'Patterns tab' you must specify which file modifications 
						will trigger goal activation - eventually you can specify there that the goals should 
						be auto-launched (Screenshot 3).
						<br/>
						<center>
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/builder/builder_configuration_dialog.png"/>
							<br/>
								<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Builder configuration : specifying file pattern</font>
							<br/>
						</center>
					</p>
					<p>
						The custom configuration will then populate the builder menu ; the goals to be launched being displayed 
						- as opposed as the configuration name (Screenshot 4). 
						<br/>
						<center>
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/builder/builder_populated_menu.png"/>
							<br/>
								<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Populated Builder configuration menu</font>
							<br/>
						</center>
						<b>Important</b> <i>Configurations with auto build set to true are not displayed in the menu.</i>
						<br/>
						Items added to the menu are disactivated until a change in the workspace matches the specified pattern,
						then the items will be activated on a per project basis, and will be disactivated once run.
					</p>
					<p>
					  <i>Important Note</i><br/>
					  While running Maven through Mevenide if you see this message 
					  <code>ZoneInfo: D:\dev\Java\jrockit-jdk1.5.0_02\lib\zi\ZoneInfoMappings (The system cannot find the path specified)</code>
					  then you will most probably need to set append '/jre' to the 'Java Home' preference in 'Maven | Locations' preference page.
					</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section>
			<p>
				<navbar prev="pom-templates.html" toc="help.html" next="repo_browsing.html"/>
			</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
