<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="rhill2@free.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
		<title>Help Page</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="POM Synchronization">
			<div id="documentContent">
				<p> 
					Mevenide POM/IDE synchronization works in similar fashion than the 
					"Team Synchronization". It supports Maven multiproject in a practical and simple way : <br/>
					A single POM is represented by a "POM node" and
					under each POM node, only the artifacts declared in this 
					underlying POM are displayed. Thus to synchronize a 
					multiproject, you have to select all relevant POMs from 
					a dialog. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Any artifact can be added or removed to and 
					from POM or .classpath. Availability of the various 
					actions depends of the current vizualisation mode. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Also if the current Eclipse project doesnot have the Java nature, user will be asked wether
					to add it or not.
				</p>
			</div>
			<subsection name="Synchronization Process">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p> 
						The synchronization view can be populated from 
						the contextual menu of either an IContainer or a pom 
						(project.xml, or more generally xml files) (Screenshot 1, below). 
						<br/>
						In the later case, only the selected file will be involved in the 
						synchronization process. 
						<br/> 
						<center> 
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/sync_project.png"/> 
							<br/> <font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> Synchronization Contextual Menu</font> <br/>
						</center> 
					</p>
					<p> 
						When triggered from an Eclipse container contextual 
						menu, if multiple project.xml files are found in the 
						selected container, user will be asked to choose which 
						POMs are to be included in the synchronization process. 
						Also if any project.xml inherits from another POM, this 
						POM can be synchronized as well (Screenshot 2). 
						<br/>
						<center> 
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/pom_choice_dialog.png"/> <br/>
							<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> POM Choice dialog</font> 
							<br/> 
						</center> 
					</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Synchronization View">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p> 
						The synchronization View provides two visualization modes : 
							<ul> 
								<li>incoming mode displays artifacts (dependencies or directories) present in pom but not in project .classpath.</li> 
								<li>outgoing mode displays artifacts present in .classpath but not found in pom.</li> 
						    </ul> 
					</p>
					<p> 
						In the future another mode will be available to show 
						conflicting artefacts. Conflicts are still to be 
						defined more clearly, but they include : 
						<ul> 
							<li>inheritance conflicts (much like the Maven Dependency Convergence)</li> 
							<li>.classpath/pom conflicts</li> 
						</ul> 
					</p>
					<p>
						<br/>
						<center>
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/synch_view.png"/>
							<br/> 
							<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Synchronization View</font>
						</center>
						<br/>
					</p>
					<p> 
						In the Outgoing mode (IDE to POM) Properties can also 
						be attached to dependencies. 
					</p>
					<p> 
						Every synchronization node is adaptable and can 
						vizualized in the properties view (Screenshot 4, 
						below). In Incoming Mode, properties sheets are 
						read-only whereas they can are writable in Outgoing 
						Mode (IDE to POM). 
						<br/> 
						<center> 
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/synch_properties.png"/>
							<br/>
							<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Properties View</font><br/>
						</center> 
					</p>
					<p> 
						You can filter the view thanks the Menu Manager using 
						either regular expressions or selecting which nodes are 
						to be filtered. This is an alternative to the 'add to 
						.mvnignore' action. 
						<br/> 
						<center> 
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/sync_filter.png"/> <br/>
							<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 5</b> Artifact Synchronization Filtering</font> 
							<br/>
						</center> 
					</p>
					<p> 
						In Incoming Mode, another action is present in 
						ActionBar that allows you to specify wether 
						project.properties file should be written or not 
						(useful while dealing with jar overriding). 
						<br/>
						<center> 
							<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/sync/toggle_overwrite.png"/> <br/>
							<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 6</b> Toggle Overwrite (Outgoing Mode only)</font> <br/>
						</center> 
					</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
		</section>
		<section>
			<p>
				<navbar prev="run.html" toc="help.html" next="edit.html"/>
			</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>