<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rhill@wanadoo.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
    <author email="ca206216@tiscali.cz">Milos Kleint</author>
    <title>Mevenide - Integrating Maven into IDEs</title>
  </properties>
<body>


	<section name="Eclipse Support">
  	  <div id="documentContent">
        <p>
    	  <b>Mevenide for Eclipse</b> distribution is composed of five different plugins : Core, Config, Grammar, Grabber and UI. 
    	  They can be found <a href="http://mevenide.codehaus.org/release">here</a>. Plugin Features are described in 
    	  <a href="mevenide-ui-eclipse/features.html">this document</a>
        </p>
        <p>
          Mevenide for Eclipse now supports Eclipse Update feature. To learn how to install Mevenide thanks the EclipseUpdate Manager,
    	  please refer to <a href="mevenide-ui-eclipse/update/index.html">this document</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
        	Requirements :
        	<ul>
        		<li>Eclipse 3.0</li>
        		<li>JDK 1.4+</li>
        		<li>Maven 1.0</li>
        	</ul>
        </p>
        <p>
        	Older releases can still be found on <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=54263">Sourceforge download page</a>.
		</p>
		<p>
			The <b>Maven PDE Plugin</b> allows Maven users to generate Eclipse plugin artifacts easily and keep trace of artifact inter-dependency. 
			To install the plugin, follow instructions on the plugin's <a href="maven-eclipse-plugin-plugin/index.html">page </a>.
		</p>
      </div>
    </section>
  	<section name="NetBeans Support">
      <div id="projects">
      <p>
        The <b>Mevenide support for the upcoming Netbeans 4.0 release</b> recognizes the Maven project type in the IDE, 
        tightly integrating maven into the IDE, allows to run arbitrary goals, edit project properties etc. 
        The complete list of features can be found <a href="mevenide-netbeans-project/features.html">here</a> and 
        You might also want to check the <a href="mevenide-netbeans-project/user-guide/index.html">User guide</a>
        which describes the features in more details and is accompanied with screenshots.
        </p>
        <p>
        The latest release 0.1 can be downloaded in <a href="download/mevenide-netbeans-0.1.zip">zip format</a>. Or it can be downloaded using the Netbeans
        Autoupdate feature. Create a new Autoupdate server in the Tools/Options dialog with the following URL: 
        <b>http://mevenide.codehaus.org/nbm_release/NBM_AutoUpdate.xml</b>
        </p>
        <p>
        	Requirements :
        	<ul>
        		<li>Netbeans 4.0, <a href="http://www.netbeans.info/downloads/download.php?a=n&amp;p=1&amp;step=2&amp;os=7&amp;lang=1&amp;rv=4.0&amp;bt=5&amp;buildnr=200407151450">Q-build from 15/Jul/2004</a> and later.</li>
        		<li>JDK 1.4+</li>
        		<li>Maven 1.0</li>
        	</ul>
        </p>
      </div>
  	  <div id="grammar">
        <p>
        The <b>mevenide-netbeans-grammar</b> module helps users when writing POM files, when customizing goals in maven.xml
        or writing their own plugins (plugin.jelly files). For details on functionality, see <a href="mevenide-netbeans-grammar/index.html">the module's pages</a>.
        </p>
    	<p>
         Latest <a href="release/mevenide-netbeans-grammar-0-2.zip">version 0.2 </a> works with Netbeans 3.6.
        </p>
        <p>
        Previous <a href="release/mevenide-netbeans-grammar-0.1.zip">version 0.1 </a> works with Netbeans 3.5.1, however it's missing some <a href="mevenide-netbeans-grammar/changes-report.html">features</a> and users are encouraged to upgrade to 3.6
        </p>
      </div>
  	  <div id="maven">
        <p>
    	  The <b>Mevenide Netbeans support for 3.6</b> allows to run arbitrary goals on a project, easily mount dependencies and
          examine project's properties files. It works with 3.5.1 and 3.6. Is not actively developed anymore, focus goes to support
          the upcoming Netbeans 4.0 which has advanced project support.
        </p>
        <p> 
        The snapshot version can be downloaded <a href="release/mevenide-ui-netbeans-0-1-SNAPSHOT.zip"> here </a>.
        </p>
      </div>
  	  <div id="plugin">
        <p>
    	The <b>Maven NBM plugin</b> allows maven users to generate Netbeans modules from their projects. To install the plugin, follow instructions on the plugin's <a href="maven-nbm-plugin/index.html">page </a>.
        </p>
      </div>
    </section>
    <section name="JBuilder Support">
  	  <div id="documentContent">
        <p></p>
      </div>
    </section>
</body>
</document>