<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rhill@wanadoo.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
    <author email="mkleint@codehaus.org">Milos Kleint</author>
    <author email="shuber2@jahia.com">Serge Huber</author>
    <title>Mevenide - Integrating Maven into IDEs</title>
  </properties>
<body>


	<section name="Eclipse Support">
  	  <div id="documentContent">
        <p>
    	  <b>Mevenide for Eclipse</b> distribution is composed of five different plugins : Core, Config, Grammar, Grabber and UI.
    	  They can be found <a href="http://mevenide.codehaus.org/release">here</a>. Plugin Features are described in
    	  <a href="mevenide-ui-eclipse/features.html">this document</a>
        </p>
        <p>
          Mevenide for Eclipse now supports Eclipse Update feature. To learn how to install Mevenide thanks the EclipseUpdate Manager,
    	  please refer to <a href="mevenide-ui-eclipse/update/index.html">this document</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
        	Requirements :
        	<ul>
        		<li>Eclipse 3.0</li>
        		<li>JDK 1.4+</li>
        		<li>Maven 1.0</li>
        	</ul>
        </p>
        <p>
        	Older releases can still be found on <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=54263">Sourceforge download page</a>.
		</p>
		<p>
			The <b>Maven PDE Plugin</b> allows Maven users to generate Eclipse plugin artifacts easily and keep trace of artifact inter-dependency.
			To install the plugin, follow instructions on the plugin's <a href="maven-eclipse-plugin-plugin/index.html">page </a>.
		</p>
      </div>
    </section>
  	<section name="NetBeans Support">
      <div id="projects">
      <p>
        The <b>Mevenide support for the Netbeans 4.1 + 5.0 IDE</b> recognizes the Maven project type in the IDE,
        tightly integrating Maven into the IDE, allows to run arbitrary goals, edit project properties etc.
        The complete list of features can be found <a href="mevenide-netbeans-project/features.html">here</a> and
        You might also want to check the <a href="mevenide-netbeans-project/user-guide/index.html">User guide</a>
        which describes the features in more details and is accompanied with screenshots. 
        </p>
        <p>
        The <b>latest release 0.9</b> can be downloaded in <a href="download/mevenide-netbeans-0.9.zip">zip format</a>.
        </p>
        <p>Or it can be downloaded using the Netbeans
        Autoupdate feature. In latest 5.0 development builds, the Mevenide autoupdate server is part of the "Infrastructure/Extra Update Centers" module on the default Netbeans autoupdate server.
Alternatively you can download and install this small <a href="download/mevenide-netbeans-autoupdate-1.0.nbm">autoupdate module</a> or create a new Autoupdate server in the Tools/Options dialog with the following URL:
        <b>http://mevenide.codehaus.org/nbm_release/NBM_AutoUpdate.xml</b>
        </p>
        <p>If you already installed some of the previous releases, updating through Autoupdate is a better option because only the updated modules get downloaded. </p>
        <p>
        	Requirements : </p>
        	<ul>
        		<li>Netbeans 4.1 or 5.0 beta <b>For 4.0 installation see note below.</b></li>
        		<li>JDK 1.4+</li>
        		<li>Maven 1.0.2</li>
        	</ul>

        <p>
        <b>Note: </b>
        The grammar module
        (editor completion for maven xml files) in 0.9 release zip will work
            with Netbeans 4.1. To get it working with 4.0 you need the <a href="../nbm_release/mevenide-netbeans-grammar-0.6.nbm">old 4.0 nbm </a>.
        </p>
      </div>
      <div id="plugin">
        <p>
    	The <b>Maven NBM plugin</b> allows maven users to generate Netbeans modules from their projects. To install the plugin, follow instructions on the plugin's <a href="maven-nbm-plugin/index.html">page </a>.
        </p>
      </div>
    </section>
    <section name="JBuilder Support">
  	  <div id="documentContent">
        <p>
    	  <b>Mevenide for JBuilder</b> distribution can be found
    	  <a href="http://mevenide.codehaus.org/release">here</a>. Plugin
    	  Features are described in
    	  <a href="mevenide-ui-jbuilder/features.html">this document</a>
        </p>
        <p>
        	Requirements :
        	<ul>
        		<li>JBuilderX</li>
        		<li>JDK 1.4+</li>
        		<li>Maven 1.0</li>
        	</ul>
        </p>
        <p>
			    The <b>Maven JBuilder OpenTool Plugin</b> allows Maven users to
			    generate JBuilder OpenTool artifacts easily.
			    To install the plugin, follow instructions on the plugin's
			    <a href="maven-jbuilder-opentool-plugin/index.html">page </a>.
		    </p>
      </div>
    </section>
    <section name="IntelliJ IDEA Support">
        <div id="documentContext">
            <p>
                <a href="mevenide-idea/index.html">Mevenide IDEA plugin</a> downloads are
                available in the <a href="mevenide-idea/downloads.html">Mevenide IDEA plugin downloads page.</a>
                You might also want to view the <a href="mevenide-idea/installation.html">installation guide</a>.
            </p>
        </div>
    </section>
</body>
</document>