<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
        <author email="mkleint@codehaus.org">Milos Kleint</author>
    	<title>Customizing Maven project</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
	<section name="Customizing Maven Project">
	  <subsection name="Basic">
	    <div id="documentContent">
		  <p>
          The Project customizer is accessible from the popup menu of the project node. It's the last item in the popup, "Properties..."<br/>
          It categorizes the content of the POM file and the project's properties into
          multiple subsections which should be self-descripting. The current implementation is able to edit
          properties and view POM file content.
          			<br/>
          The Resolve Values checkbox allows one to switch between 2 modes.
          <ul>
            <li><p>When the checkbox is unselected, all editable fields are editable and are displayed exactly as defined in the project files.</p></li>
            <li><p>When resolving values, the fields are not editable but one can see to what values the properties definitions resolve in the 
            current context of the project. If a value cannot be resolved, it still displayed in the unresolved state.</p> 
            </li>
          </ul>
          <p>
          This feature can be used to examine and debug the project definitions.
          </p>
          
			<br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/projectproperties.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> Maven project customizer</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
		  </p>
          <p>
			<br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/projectprops2.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> Maven project customizer - Dependencies</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
		  </p>          
            <p>
            The UI also shows what plugins are installed within the project's context. 
            It tries to guess which plugins are used (based on used properties within the project scope)
            and allows one to view and change the plugin's setup.
            </p>
          <p>
			<br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/projectplugins.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Maven project customizer - Plugins</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
		  </p>          
	    </div>
	  </subsection>
	  <subsection name="Definition layers">
	  	<div id="documentContent">
		  <p>
          The properties can be defined in multiple files in maven.
          </p>
          <ul>
          <li> <p>There are the project.properties and build.properties files in the project folder.</p></li>
          <li> <p> There is the build.properties file in the user directory, which is capable of influencing behaviour of all projects.</p></li>
          <li> <p> Then there's project and build property files in the parent's project directory. (If the POM file defines the "extends" tag.)</p></li>
          </ul>
          <p>
          To let the user know where the givem property is defined, the customizer places a coloured triangle icon
          next to all property definitions. By clicking the icon, one can move the property definition.
          <br/>
          Note: By moving to the build property file in the user dir, one doesn't influence only the current project but all projects.
			<br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/redefinelocation.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Changing location of property definition</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
            
		  </p>
	    </div>
	  </subsection>
      <subsection name="Global execution options">
	  	<div id="documentContent">
		  <p>
          To influence the execution of maven, you can define what commaond line switches are used when
          executing Maven. These are not project based, but global for use in the IDE, don't influence
          maven when used on the command-line.
			<br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/options.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 5</b> Global Options</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
          
          </p>
      </div>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Maven Goals to IDE Mappings">
	  	<div id="documentContent">
		  <p>
          Apart from changing standard maven properties, one can also redefine what 
          common IDE building actions mean in the maven sense. So for your webapp you can
          make the IDE's Build action to deploy the built app to the server for testing.
          <br/>
          These values are like common Maven project properties, which means you can put the definitions into cvs
          and let everyone build the project the same way.
          For detailed description of the properties, see <a href="../properties.html"> page </a> describing the properties definition in detail.
          <br/>
			<center>
				<img border="1px" src="../images/screenshots/projectgoals.png"/>
				<br/>
				<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 6</b> Changing goals definition</font>
				<br/>
			</center>
          
          </p>
      </div>
      </subsection>
	</section>
	<section>
		<p>
			<navbar prev="reports.html" toc="index.html" next="completion.html"/>
		</p>
	</section>
  </body>
</document>