<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
        <author email="mkleint@codehaus.org">Milos Kleint</author>
	<title>Features</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
	<section name="Features List">
	  <div id="documentContent">
		<p>
		  Implemented features fall into these categories :
          </p>
		  <ul>
			<li><p><a href="#Maven Project recognition">Maven Project recognition</a></p></li>
			<li><p><a href="#Maven Launcher">Maven Launcher</a></p></li>
			<li><p><a href="#POM Customizer">POM Visual Customizer</a></p></li>
			<li><p><a href="#Running and Debugging">Running and Debugging application</a></p></li>
			<li><p><a href="#Browsing">Browsing remote repositories</a></p></li>
		  </ul>
          <p>
          For a detailed walkthrough describing the feautures accompanied with picures, see the <a href="user-guide/index.html">User Guide</a>
          
		</p>
	  </div>
  </section>
  <section name="Maven Project recognition">
	<div id="documentContent">
	  <p>Maven projects are recognized in the IDE by the Mevenide module. No synchronization is needed since
          the module retrieves and stores data directly to/from Maven project files.</p>
	  <p>
		<ul>
		  <li><p>All kind of sources and resources easily accessible.</p></li>
		  <li><p>Dependencies recognized and code completion database created on the fly.</p></li>
		  <li><p>Jar Override Support for dependecies</p></li>
		  <li><p>Updates dynamically once project files are edited.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
      </div>
  </section>
  <section name="Maven Launcher">
	<div id="documentContent">
	  <p>
		<ul>
		  <li><p>Direct integration with menu action and keyboard shotcuts for Build/Rebuild/Clean etc. 
                  See <a href="properties.html" class="documentLink"> how to customize</a> what gets run in the IDE.</p></li>
		  <li><p>List of all available goals - plugin-defined ones as well as custom ones for project.</p></li>
		  <li><p>Possibility to define your own goal-launching popup menu.</p></li>
		  <li><p>Output to the output window. For compilation and tests hyperlinking to errors.</p></li>
                  <li><p>Pmd, checkstyle, findbugs and announcement reports also accessible from the output window along with annotations in the editor.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	  <p>
		<u>Known limitations</u><br/>
		<ul>
            <li><p>Executes maven as external process. Slower invokation.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	</div>
  </section>
  <section name="POM Customizer">
	<div id="documentContent">
          <p>
		<ul>
		  <li><p>Visual customization of Maven project.</p></li>
		  <li><p>Locating the definitions is easy without searching multiple files, 
                   possible to move between location easily.</p></li>
                   <li><p>Creation of new Maven projects from templates.</p></li>
                   <li><p>Lists all current plugins and their properties.</p></li>                   
		</ul>
	  </p>
	  <p>
		<u>Known limitations</u><br/>
		<ul>
        		<li><p>Currently not all pages are implemented.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	</div>
  </section>
  <section name="Running and Debugging">
	<div id="documentContent">
          <p>
		<ul>
		  <li><p>Able to run the project or single classes.</p></li>
           <li><p>Able to run test suite or single test from IDE.</p></li>
           <li><p>Can debug the application, a single class or single test.</p></li>
           <li><p>For web applications, it's possible to deploy to a web server using Cargo.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	  <p>
		<u>Known limitations</u><br/>
		<ul>
			<li><p>Currently the IDE can only attach to the debugged JVM it starts. Later IDE can also listen etc.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	</div>
  </section>
  <section name="Browsing">
	<div id="documentContent">
          <p>
		<ul>
	  <li><p>Able to browse remote and local repositories.</p></li>
          <li><p>See each repo separately, or merged together into one tree.</p></li>
          <li><p>Can download artifacts.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	  <p>
		<u>Known limitations</u><br/>
		<ul>
    <li><p>Refreshing of the views not implemented yet.</p></li>
    <li><p>Searching also not implemented.</p></li>
		</ul>
	  </p>
	</div>
  </section>
  </body>
</document>
