<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  	<properties>
    	<author email="shuber2@jahia.com">Serge Huber</author>
    	<title>Maven JBuilder OpenTool</title>
  	</properties>
  	
	<body>
		<section name="Overview">
			
			<subsection name="Introduction">
				<div id="documentContent">
				<p>This tool enables you to integrate Maven into your JBuilder project !
				For those unfamiliar with Maven, here is the definition of the project from
				the <a href="http://maven.apache.org">Maven web site</a> :</p>
				<p><i> Maven is a Java project management and project comprehension tool.
					Maven is based on the concept of a project object model (POM) in that all
					the artifacts produced by Maven are a result of consulting a well defined
					model for your project. Builds, documentation, source metrics, and source
					cross-references are all controlled by your POM</i></p>
				<p>Maven offers tools to automatically manage your external library dependencies
					from a central repository, offers lots of plugins that can do things as
					various as compiling your code, verifying that the code in the project
					complies to coding standard, generate reports and web sites, generate SQL
					scripts from XML schema description files, etc... It is also now the tool
					used in a lot of open source projects, as it handles all the nitty-gritty
					of a project and leaves you more time to do the coding</p>
				<p>This tool allows you to directly trigger Maven Goals (equivalent to Ant
					Targets) from your JBuilder project, including even setting dependencies on
					a Maven goal for a runtime configuration, just you can do with an Ant
					Target. This tool is also capable of generating a JBuilder library file
					containing all the Maven project dependencies, so that you may include the
					library file in the project and compile using the correct dependencies.
					Future versions of this tool might bring more features, such as
					editing the project file with IDE Wizards.</p>
					</div>
			</subsection>
						
			<subsection name="Credits">
				<div id="documentContent">
				<p>
				  Written by Serge Huber (<a href="mailto:shuber2@jahia.com">shuber2@jahia.com</a>)
				</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
			
			<subsection name="History">
				<div id="documentContent">
				<p>Version 0.2<br />Updated to support JBuilder 2005</p>
				<p>Version 0.1<br />Initial release</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>

		</section>
    </body>
</document>