<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
    	<author email="ca206216@tiscali.cz">Milos Kleint</author>
        <title>Overview</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Project Overview">
        <div id="documentContent">
        <p> This project is a simple XML grammar code completion Netbeans module which gives the user access to 
        basic maven/jelly-taglib elements and attributes.
        It currently works with Netbeans 3.6 and 4.0. (If anyone wants a release for 3.5, send me an email)
        </p>
	</div>
   </section>
   <section name="Versions">
      <div id="documentContent">
      	<p>
   	  Currently the 0.2 version is available for download which works with Netbeans 3.6. 
      </p>
      <p>
      The same (or later) version is bundled with the project support module for 4.0. 
      </p>
   	  </div>
    </section>

    <section name="Download/Installing">
      <div id="documentContent">
      <p>
            To install the product, get the <a href="http://mevenide.codehaus.org/download/mevenide-netbeans-grammar-0-2.tar.gz" class="documentLink">tar.gz</a> or 
            the <a href="http://mevenide.codehaus.org/download/mevenide-netbeans-grammar-0-2.zip" class="documentLink">zip archive</a> which contain nbm files.
            Extract them to a temporary location and install the nbm files using your IDE's "Tools/Update Center" wizard.
   	  </p>
      <p>
      If you're using 4.0 builds, please <a href="../download.html">download</a> the whole project support.
      </p>
   	  </div>
    </section>
    
    <section name="How It Works">
        <div id="documentContent">
           <p>
           The module provides code completion in various places of the edited file. The default keyboard shortcut to 
           invoke the code completion is <code>Ctrl-Space</code>. Then you can navigate in the provided list or
           type more characters which results in updated, narrowed completion offering.
           </p>
           <p>
           Firstly you can get a list of available namespaces. They are sorted alphabetically and include default jelly taglibraries,
           maven specific jelly taglibraries and also dynamic taglibraries originating from the maven plugins.
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_namespace.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b>Completing namespaces.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
           </p>
           <p> Later when writing the content, you will be offered standard tags, such as <code> goal</code> or <code> pregoal </code>, but also tags from the included
            taglibraries. These are sorted in the following manner. Namespaces only first, standard tags, and then tags from included taglibraries sorted by taglib name and tag name.
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_tag.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b>Completing tags.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_dynamic_tag.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b>Completing tags from a given taglibrary.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
           </p>
           <p> 
                After choosing a tag, you can easily get a list of available, known attributes defined for this element. These are sorted alphabetically. Again only those that match the already typed characters are displayed.
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_attribute.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b>Completing attributes.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_dynamic_attribute.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 5</b>Completing dynamic attributes.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
           </p>
           <p> In attributes values, you can get various completions. 
           <ul> <li><p>After typing "maven." in any attribute value, you get a list of 
           plugins' property keys that modify the plugins' behaviour. </p> </li>
            <li><p>For goal related attributes, you get a list of applicable goals.
            </p> </li>           
           </ul>
				<center>
					<img border="1px" src="images/cc_plugin_props.png"/>
					<br/><br/>
					<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 6</b>Completing plugin property keys.</font>
					<br/><br/>
				</center>
           </p>
          </div>
    </section>
  </body>

</document>