<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  	<properties>
    	<author email="shuber2@jahia.com">Serge Huber</author>
    	<title>Maven JBuilder OpenTool Features</title>
  	</properties>

	<body>
		<section name="Features">
			
			<subsection name="Maven goal integration">
				<div id="documentContent">
				  <p>The list of goals you can use in your project is completely integrated with
				  JBuilder's target system, so you may easily use Maven goals when building or
				  even running programs.<br/>
				  <br/>
				  <center>
				    <img border="1px" src="images/screenshots/browser.png"/><br/>
					Project browser integration<br/>
					<br/>
					<img border="1px" src="images/screenshots/messages.png"/><br/>
					Maven output in message window<br/>
					<br/>
				  </center>
				  </p>
				  <p>For example you can call a deployment Maven goal just before running your
				  program<br/>
				  <center>
				    <img border="1px" src="images/screenshots/run_config.png"/><br/>
					Runtime configuration goal integration<br/>
					<br/>
				  </center>
				  </p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
			
			<subsection name="Maven settings">
				<div id="documentContent">
				  <p>You can also set some setting on how Maven execution will happen :<br/>
				  <center>
				    <img border="1px" src="images/screenshots/project_properties.png"/><br/>
					Maven settings for project<br/>
					<br/>
				  </center>
				  </p>
				</div>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Automatic Dependency Library Generation">
				<div id="documentContent">
				<p>This tool also automatically updates a JBuilder library called
				   <b>MavenAutoUpdated.library</b> that is generated in the same directory as the
				   JBuilder project (*.jpx) file. <br/>
				   <center>
				     <img border="1px" src="images/screenshots/autoupdated_library.png"/><br/>
 					 Automatically updated JAR library<br/>
					 <br/>
				   </center>
				   It is generated from the Maven project
				   descriptor file (project.xml), which contains all the JAR dependencies. In
				   order for this function to work, you must have inserted the <b>project.xml</b>
				   in your project and the JARs *must* be already present in
				   the maven local repository, which is assumed to be located in :
				</p>
				<p>${user.home}/.maven/repository</p>
				<p>You can therefore simply include all Maven dependencies as a required library
					for the JBuilder project and you should then be able to compile the project
					with JBuilder in sync with Maven. Note that this OpenTool does not automatically
					insert the library into the project, since this is something that might not
					be desired, but the library file will always be updated nonetheless (should
					you want to add it later on).
				</p>
				</div>
			</subsection>
						
		</section>
	
	</body>
	
</document>