<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Changes</title>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <release version="0.1" date="unreleased"
                 description="The initial version. Focuses on integration with Mevenide, and catching up on missing features.">
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="update">
                JetBrains has upgraded the JDOM version they use in the IDE from 0.8 to 1.0,
                which enables us now to restore the original plugin architecture to a single
                Maven project and remove the custom class loader implementation since it is
                no longer needed. Therefor, reintegrate <i>mevenide-idea-main</i>,
                <i>mevenide-idea-model</i> and <i>mevenide-idea-master</i> back into a single
                project called <i>mevenide-idea</i>.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Automatically update goals tree if either the <i>maven.xml</i> or
                <i>project.xml</i> files are changed. Synchronization will occur
                whether the change came from inside the IDE (e.g. the user has
                edited the files) or from outside the IDE (e.g. opening notepad
                and manually modifying the files).
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Showing goal descriptions in Goals tool window/pane.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Added a short installation guide.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="update">
                Split project into subprojects:
                <ul>
                    <li>mevenide-idea-master: a template parent project for the other modules</li>
                    <li>
                        mevenide-idea-main: the main project - provides the UI and plugin wrapper.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        mevenide-idea-model: interacts with mevenide and exposes project information
                        for the mevenide-idea-main module.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="update">
                Modified code base to use Mevenide libraries instead of custom code
                that does the same.
            </action>
            <action dev="arikkfir" type="add">
                Created initial code base of the plugin. Current code supports:
                <ul>
                    <li>Specifying a POM file on a per-module basis.</li>
                    <li>Specifying "favorite" goals for each module, for easy access.</li>
                    <li>
                        An Ant-like tool window displaying each IDEA module's available
                        goals, as defined in <i>maven.xml</i>.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Execution of selected goal(s) in a dedicated execution console,
                        much like the standard <i>Run</i>console of IDEA. Each execution
                        can be stopped, or paused.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Specifying a different Maven home than the one defined in your
                        <i>MAVEN_HOME</i>environment variable and PATH.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </action>
        </release>

    </body>
</document>

