<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

    <properties>
        <author email="arikkfir@gmail.com">Arik Kfir</author>
        <title>Mevenide IDEA integration</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
                Welcome to the MevenIDE IDEA Integration project! This project
                aims to integrate <a href="http://maven.apache.org">Maven</a> in every possible way
                into <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com">JetBrain</a>'s IntelliJ IDEA.
            </p>
            <p>
                Current integration features include:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        A graphical Project Object Model (POM) editor. The editor includes a
                        standard text editor, as well as an intuitive user interface for
                        editing the various aspects of a project.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Full synchronization between the POM text editor and the graphical
                        POM editor, as well as with POM modifications outside the IntelliJ
                        IDE.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Automatic discovery of POM files (<i>project.xml</i> and
                        <i>maven.xml</i>) for each IntelliJ module. The plugin will detect if you
                        create one of these files either from inside the IDE or from outside, and
                        will respond appropriately.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        A special Maven tool window displaying the available Maven goals for the
                        project. The pane shows goals defined in the module's
                        <i>maven.xml</i> file, and common goals, marked as "favorites" in
                        the module settings dialog.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Execution of selected goal(s) in a dedicated execution console which
                        supports stop, pause, and re-run. The console supports copying the Maven
                        output into the clipboard or into a text file.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Compilation errors reported by Maven in the execution console are displayed
                        as links, which open the appropriate source code file at the appropriate
                        location.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Auto-detection of your Maven home (via the <i>MAVEN_HOME</i> environment
                        variable), and support for specifying a different Maven home (does not
                        modify the environment variable).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Easy installation via the IntelliJ IDEA plugins manager.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Support for assigning shortcut keys (hot-keys) for specific goals for a
                        specific module in the IDE (no need to find the goal in the Goals tool
                        window).
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <subsection name="News">
                <p style="font-size: larger; font-weight: bold">
                    30 May 2005 - MevenIDE for IDEA 0.1 has been released!
                </p>
                <p>
                    This is the first release of the Mevenide for IDEA - and
                    brings Maven support for the popular IntelliJ IDEA, including
                    the ability to execute goals, a graphical POM editor,
                    automatic jumping from Maven errors to source code, and much more.
                </p>
                <p>
                    See
                    <a href="installation.html">installation instructions</a>for
                    information on how to download and install.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Downloading and Installing">
            <p>
                Mevenide for IDEA releases can be found <a href="downloads.html">here</a>. If,
                however, you wish to use the latest snapshot version, you may find it
                <a href="http://dist.codehaus.org/mevenide/distributions">here</a> - search
                for files named <i>mevenide-idea-X.Y-SNAPSHOT.zip</i> (or ".tar.gz").
                Snapshot versions must be installed manually - see the
                <a href="installation.html">installation manual</a>for details.
            </p>
        </section>

        <section name="Help Wanted!">
            <p>
                The Mevenide IDEA integration project is quite new and we are looking for
                volunteers - you can help! If you like the IntelliJ IDEA, and you like Maven -
                come and help us write the best IDEA plugin yet!
            </p>
            <p>
                To participate - please contact us via our
                <a href="mail-lists.html">mailing lists</a>.
            </p>
        </section>

        <section name="Compatibility">
            <p>
                Currently the plugin is only supported on the IntelliJ IDEA Early Access Program
                (EAP) dubbed "Irida". It cannot be run on the 4.5 version.
            </p>
            <p>
                There is, however, a port of the plugin for the 4.5 version with provides the basic
                features such as per-module POM attachment, favorite goals, running goals and
                jumping to source code from Maven error messages. It is available
                <a href="http://www.codehaus.org/~arik/dist/mevenide-idea-4.5.4.zip">here</a>.
                <br/>
                NOTE: This is a source code distribution, and you will have to build it from
                source code. If you do, make sure you compile the classes using IDEA, since
                the plugin utilizes the IDEA UI designer, which injects bytecode into the
                classes. There is an Ant script inside, but it does not perform the code
                injection, and you will get exceptions. The Ant script DOES, however, provide
                an Ant task for it, but does not activate it.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>