<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
    	<author email="rhill2@free.fr">Gilles Dodinet</author>
        <title>Help Page</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
    	<section name="Jelly Edition">
			<subsection name="Editor">
				<div id="documentContent">
					<p> When editing a Jelly file, you will be offered standard tags, such as <code> goal</code> or <code> pregoal </code>, but also tags from the included
					taglibraries (Screenshots 1 and 2). These are sorted in the following manner : Werkz tags, and then tags from included taglibraries sorted by taglib name and tag name.
					<br/><br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/top-level-nodes.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 1</b> Completing tags</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
				</p>
				<p>
					Please note that Werkz tags are only offered with the 'Maven Jelly Editor' : Generic Jelly editor doesnot propose them.
					<br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/goal-name.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 2</b> Completing tags from a given taglibrary</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
			   </p>
			   <p> 
					After choosing a tag, you can easily get a list of available, known attributes defined for this element (Screenshot 3). These are sorted alphabetically. Again only those that match the already typed characters are displayed.
					<br/><br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/attribute-name.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 3</b> Completing attributes</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
				</p>
				<p>
					Last, you have proposals for attainGoal name attribute : proposed values are the list of global goals and custom ones. For now, the list is computed from the previously saved version (not from the buffer).
					<br/><br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/attaingoal-attribute-value.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 4</b> Completing attributes value</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
			   </p>
			  </div>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="Outline page">
				<p>
					The 'Maven Jelly Editor' comes with an outline (Screenshot 5) that displays the list of available goals (global and custom). This list can filtered via the Menu Manager : it is possible to filter through regular expressions, specific names,
					or by category - custom vs. global (Screenshot 6, below). Doubleclicking a goal launches that goal, allowing a fast preview of the current behavior. Please note that the 'Run offline' option in the Outline page is not active yet.
				</p>
				<p>
					<br/><br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/outline.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 5</b> maven.xml Outline page</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
				</p>
				<p>
					<br/><br/>
					<center>
						<img border="1px" src="images/outline_filter.png"/>
						<br/><br/>
						<font size="-1"><b>Screenshot 6</b> Filtering Outline page</font>
						<br/><br/>
					</center>
				</p>
			</subsection>
        </section>
        <section>
			<p>
				<navbar prev="edit.html" toc="help.html" next="wizard.html"/>
			</p>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>