<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>maven-nbm-plugin Goals</title>
    <author>Milos Kleint (ca206216@tiscali.cz)</author>
  </properties>
  
  <body>
  	<section name="Primary Goals">
  		<div id="documentContent">
  		<table>
  		  <tr>
  		  	<th>Goal</th>
  		  	<th>Description</th>
  		  </tr>	
  		  <tr>
            <td>nbm:jar</td>
            <td><p>Creates a netbeans module jar. </p>
            <p>
            Basic Netbeans manifest attributes are generated by default.
            It includes the possibility to add additional netbeans manifest entries 
            using the <code> maven.nbm.manifest </code> property.
            The generated defaults only apply when the attributes are not defined
            in the manifest entry of the jar or the <code> maven.nbm.manifest </code> file.
            </p>
            <p>
            <code> OpenIDE-Module-Module-Dependencies </code> attribute is also constructed. However, only the dependencies marked with property <code> netbeans.module.dep </code>
            are included.
            </p>
            <p>
            <code> Class-Path </code> attribute is also constructed, only for dependencies with property <code> netbeans.module.ext </code>
            </p>
            <p>
            Also localizable attributes <code> OpenIDE-Module-Display-Category OpenIDE-Module-Name OpenIDE-Module-Short-Description OpenIDE-Module-Long-Description </code>
            are defined, only in the case the manifest entry doesn't include the <code> OpenIDE-Module-Localizing-Bundle </code> attribute. If that one is defined, it is assumed that the attributes are defined in the 
            properties file.
            </p>
            </td> 
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>nbm:nbm</td>
            <td><p>Creates the nbm file. It includes the module jar, and also it's dependencies if they are marked in this manner: </p>
            <source><p><![CDATA[
                <properties>
                  	<netbeans.module.ext>true</netbeans.module.ext>
                </properties>
            ]]></p></source>
            <p>
            The license file is included if defined.
            </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
<!--          <tr>
            <td>nbm:create-library-artifacts</td>
            <td><p>Creates the nbm file(s) for dependencies marked by this property
            <source><![CDATA[
                <properties>
                  	<netbeans.lib.generate>true</netbeans.lib.generate>
                </properties>
            ]]></source>
            </p>
            <p>
            It creates a simple Netbeans module jar and puts the dependency on the module's classpath. 
            Your own module can then declare dependency on this module. That is especially handy when multiple projects share dependencies.
            </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          -->
          <tr>
            <td>nbm:autoupdate</td>
            <td><p>Creates a Netbeans autoupdate structure.
            </p>
            <p>
            For nbms collected by the <code>nbm:collect-nbms</code> the goal generates the xml describing the autoupdate server.
            That can be used for setting up an autoupdate server.
            </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
  		</table>
        
        
  		</div>
  	</section>
  	<section name="Secondary Goals">
  		<div id="documentContent">
  		<table>
  		  <tr>
  		  	<th>Goal</th>
  		  	<th>Description</th>
  		  </tr>	
  		  <tr>
            <td>nbm:fill-repository</td>
            <td>
            <p>
            This goal extracts Netbeans module jars from the Netbeans IDE/Platform installation and puts them
            into the local maven repository. It will figure out the correct version information 
            by examining the module jar's manifest.
            </p>
            </td>
            </tr>
  		  <tr>
            <td>nbm:prepare-nbm-resources</td>
            <td>
<p>            This goal is a prerequisite of nbm:nbm, it copies all the required resources into
            the <code><![CDATA[${maven.nbm.build.dir}/netbeans]]></code> file structure which is later used to
            build the nbm file. By default copies the netbeans module jar and all the jars specified by the
            Class-Path: manifest attribute. This goal can be used in the custom maven.xml scripts
            to copy additional resources that should be included into the nbm.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
  		  <tr>
            <td>nbm:install</td>
            <td>
<p> Installs the NBM and the jar with netbeans enhanced manifest attributes into the local repository.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
  		  <tr>
            <td>nbm:collect-nbms</td>
            <td>
<p> Collects all the project's NBM files (the primary artifact. <!-- and also possible generated NBMs for the dependencies. -->
Default target location is <code><![CDATA[${maven.build.dir}/nbm_release]]></code> directory. 
That location is later used by the <code>nbm:autoupdate</code> goal to 
create the autoupdate server file structure.
</p>
            </td>
          </tr>
  		</table>
  		</div>
  	</section>
  	
  </body>
</document>
